QUINCY [IN RUSSIAN]:
MAN:
Quincy. stack them two and two?
RACHEL:
We'll need 20 amps for a new circuit...
...at least three laptops.
four external hard drives.
- You can leave that right there. Thank you.
MAN: Yes. ma'am.
- [IN ENGLISH] Well?
- They're gonna get us what we need.
If you mean to do this. we're gonna need
a much more comprehensive cooling system.
- And I have told them as much.
- Vials. syringes.
- We're running low on everything.
- Quincy. I know.
We will replenish
once we get to Guantanamo Bay.
I'm gonna ask a question.
- And I want you to listen to me.
- Go ahead.
You're working 20 hours a day.
You're not sleeping.
This is a marathon. not a sprint.
Let me go off-ship this time.
I'll think about it.
Hup. fire!
Fire! Fire!
Ready. halt. Headshot!
Weapons on safe.
Cossetti. keep that right arm blocked.
Make sure you lean into that recoil.
COSSETTI: Sir.
- Next group!
How are they looking?
Janowitz has an eye.
Harris and Cossetti have the balls.
- Depends on what we're gonna need there.
- Balls. We need the balls.
Yes. sir.
TAC Team One advance!
TAC Two. let's go!
Advance!
Damn it. Miller!
- Muzzle down!
- Sorry. sir!
Sorry's not gonna do us any good
when you shoot his head off at Gitmo!
Now TAC One. TAC Two. reset.
Do it again!
- It's gonna take time. sir.
- Time is something we don't have.
Every day we don't come home
with a vaccine...
...is a day another half a million people die.
I want to make sure they're ready.
- You'll get them there.
- Yes. sir.
TAC Team One advance!
Ripped By mstoll
You will operate on three-man
watch teams. 10-hour shifts.
Captain wants a complete log
of every transmission.
You may be hearing emergency-broadcast...
...and radio distress calls
from around the world.
But we do not. under any circumstances.
respond or transmit.
Strict EMCON.
Our position must remain secure.
- So the Russians are still following us?
- We don't know that.
Well. somebody shot a nuke
over our heads outside France.
- You been in CIC the last five days?
- Yes. ma'am.
ALISHA: Were there any surface
or subsurface contacts?
- No. ma'am.
- Then let's not start spreading rumors.
They can be as contagious as the virus.
This room will be restricted access.
Comms specialists only. Got it?
Yes. ma'am.
Chief engineer? Give me a status.
Sir. The fuel from the cruise ship
is absolutely filthy and just keeps degrading.
If we don't hit pay dirt at Gitmo.
we might as well break out the oars.
Don't wanna burn through our nozzles.
Take a couple engines off-line.
No can do. sir. CO's ordered flank speed
all the way to Gitmo.
- He's up to date on the condition of the fuel?
- He is. sir.
DANNY:
Here you go. boy.
- How's training going?
- I don't know exactly what we're training for.
Just gonna find a bunch of corpses.
It must be tough...
...having to train someone
to replace Frankie.
I'm getting sick of this grub.
I hope we find something other than
mashed potatoes and cling peaches in Cuba.
[DANNY WHISTLES & DOG WOOFS]
- Danny.
- What?
You're not dealing.
Frankie's dead.
So are my parents. probably.
and so are yours...
...and everyone else's
in the whole damn world.
So. what exactly is the proper way
for me to be dealing?
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
We're low on food.
Low on water. We need help.
We're in a warehouse off of Route 17.
I'm with my two boys. so--
WOMAN [OVER RADIO]:
If you can hear my voice...
...we need medical assistance. please.
We are right at the--
MILLER: I don't really feel comfortable
speaking in public...
...but I just wanted to say something
about my mother...
...who's in Iowa somewhere. I hope.
God. please look over her and keep her safe.
JETER:
What's her name. son?
Barbara. Barbara Miller.
This is her.
I'd like to say a prayer for my boyfriend.
His name's Mickey.
Well. his real name's Morris.
I....
He hates having his picture taken...
...so I've just got this one.
It's a selfie.
O'CONNOR:
This is my father. Paul.
My brothers. Nate and Ronnie.
Couldn't get through to them.
so I don't know where they are.
Like most of us. I guess.
But. um. what keeps me going...
...is the idea that we might
be able to help them somehow.
You know. maybe there is a reason
we were out there in the Arctic all that time.
Maybe this is God's plan for us.
Amen to that.
ALL:
Amen.
RACHEL:
The rules of the virus are these.
It's airborne. You can get it
from anyone who's a carrier...
...anyone manifesting the disease.
even a recently deceased corpse.
Typical symptoms are lethargy
and a cough...
...followed by bleeding sores
and hemorrhaging...
...ending in dementia and total blood loss.
- How long is the incubation period?
RACHEL: Three to five days.
At least. that's what I understood
from my last contact with the CDC.
And when was that?
Three weeks ago
when we were in the Arctic.
Are you saying the incubation period
can change?
The virus has been mutating for some time...
...although I believe now
that it's been altered. it's stabilized.
You believe?
What about animals?
If you're concerned about Halsey.
dogs happen to be immune.
Animals can contract the disease.
They can't transmit it to humans.
- I thought the birds were the original carriers.
RACHEL: The birds were the carriers.
The virus jumped.
probably from their feces...
...to a mammal before mutating
and landing on us.
After several mutations.
it was artificially altered.
It is that version of the mutated strain...
...that is currently devastating our planet.
So CBR gear at all times.
except outside in open spaces.
- Masks can be off to preserve your oxygen.
- And inside?
RACHEL: One infected person
could jeopardize this entire ship...
...simply by breathing.
Question. Before we send our men
into a hot zone...
...if the virus keeps mutating...
...and you haven't heard from homeland
in almost a month...
...how can you be sure
of what you're sure of?
If I had any doubt about what I was saying...
...I would tell you.
I would hope so.
I see you've cooled off.
- I'm fine.
- Then what was that?
Just asking questions.
You were undermining her
in front of the officers.
I know. Mike.
She lied to us for four months.
While she was talking to home every week...
...we didn't even get a chance
to warn our families.
- We're just supposed to get over that?
- Yeah. we are.
She's got a long way to go
before she earns my trust.
- That's all.
- What about me?
There's no Navy. no infrastructure.
no food or fuel supply.
We don't know what we're gonna find. and
we're gonna have to improvise every step.
- Now. I'm gonna need my XO--
- To fall in line?
To execute.
Whether or not he agrees with my decisions.
Now. I'm gonna ask you one time
and one time only:
Are you with me?
I took an oath.
and I still respect the chain of command.
- That wasn't my question.
- I'm with you.
You really think she can do this?
She's the only hope we got.
PILOT:
Coming over Gitmo now.
Negative visual contact.
Negative movement.
DANNY:
Where is everybody?
PILOT:
Same on thermals.
We have zero. copy. zero ground movement.
There were 9000 people stationed there.
Food warehouse and hospital look
spread out. Fuel rig's all the way up there.
That's why we're gonna go with three teams.
I'll take the warehouse.
You'll hit the hospital.
- Fuel team ready?
- We are. sir.
Stay frosty. Something about this
doesn't feel right.
Yes. sir.
You're absolutely the most
obstinate person I've met.
- You know that?
- I don't know everyone you've met.
- It's insane.
- If I let you go. you'll be out there all week.
- You're too meticulous.
- What if something happens?
He's right. We can't risk you leaving.
- Thank you. I'll get my suit.
CHANDLER: Not so fast. doctor.
- We can't risk either of you.
QUINCY: That's flattering--
How do you plan on getting us the supplies?
Not to underestimate
your men's capabilities...
...but it's highly unlikely
they're gonna identify what we need.
If we can knock an ICBM out of the sky.
I think we can handle this.
An officer will escort you both to CIC.
And what about you. captain?
What if something happens to you?
The mission will go on...
...in Commander Slattery's
very capable hands.
After last night's performance.
I'm not so sure.
Well. we're all out on a limb here. aren't we?
Vulture Team is feet dry on the east beach.
Proceed to first objective.
Approaching the south gate.
Cobra Team is approaching the hospital.
Over here.
We've attached a helmet cam
to Lieutenant Green.
We can see everything he does
and communicate to him by UHF.
So you can get what you need.
It'll be fine.
That's my chair.
I understand people aren't
particularly thrilled with me...
...but I had orders.
From the Pentagon.
KARA:
We understand orders.
We follow them every day.
Masks on.
- Masks on.
CRUZ: All right. masks up.
We've got 60 minutes of air at max conserve.
Chief Lynn. XO.
Fuel team's approaching the rigs.
- Expect to receive fuel within 15 minutes.
LYNN [OVER RADIO]: Roger. XO.
We need to find the valve wheel.
It couldn't have gone far.
CHANDLER [OVER RADIO]: The Vulture Team
heading due south sector. All's quiet.
[METAL CLANGS]
Well. you bucking for a Silver Star.
aren't you. Miller?
You can't teach courage like that.
Follow our lead.
We'll be in and out in less than an hour.
- Was it too much?
- Just enough.
RIOS:
Don't touch that.
You discharge that you'll flood the whole
engineering room with poisonous Halon gas.
Uh. my state room is freezing.
and I was told these levers...
...might shut off the AC to my space.
- By who?
- I don't know. One of the enlisted men.
Do us a favor.
Don't touch anything on the ship.
- Of course.
- If you need help. ask for it.
- Very sorry.
- Okay.
[GAGS]
Eyes in front of you.
And do not puke in your mask.
KARA:
ls that what it was like on the cruise ship?
None of them wanna talk about it.
That's because there are no words.
Nathan James. Tiger Team. we're all set.
SLATTERY [OVER RADIO]:
Copy that. We are ready to receive.
CCS Bridge. your martini is on its way.
One. two. three.
One more time. We got it. One. two. three.
[HUMMING]
Bridge. CCS. fueling commenced.
- We're in.
- You're looking for steroids.
Interferon. Ribavirin.
Any broad-spectrum antibiotics
you can find.
We need plastic ware.
monitoring equipment. culture plates.
Show me the whole room.
Bring it round slowly.
Over to the right.
Back. back. back! Back to the left.
Move forward. Closer.
- That's it. That's a centrifuge.
DANNY [OVER RADIO]: Got it.
CHANDLER:
No apparent activity in Sector Charlie 5.
Vulture Team proceeding directly to objective.
Copy that. Vulture One.
Masks.
TEX:
I'm an American! Get the hell out of there!
Don't! Get out! Stop it!
Get the hell out of there!
MAN 1:
Burk! Get up. get up. get going! Weapons.
[MAN 2 SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
I'm American. I'm friendly.
- I'm a friendly American.
- This is Vulture.
We're under attack
by unknown number of hostiles.
Stand by for fire mission.
Set General Quarters!
Threat warning red. weapons tight!
General Quarters. General Quarters.
All hands. man your battle stations.
Light off mount five one.
Shift to local ready surface.
Vulture One. Nathan James.
do we have a target?
Negative. Cobra Team.
Tiger Team. be advised.
Hostiles operating on base.
IEDs are being employed. Set fipcom delta.
WOMAN:
Copy that. Vulture One.
- Master Chief. we need guns up.
- I'm on it. O'Connor.
This is Cobra Team. We're a half mile
south-southeast from your port ops.
Say the word and we will provide backup.
Negative. I don't want you walking
into an ambush. Stay on mission.
Yes. sir.
- Back up!
- Jesus. guys. I'm on your side!
I said. back up!
I'm not sick.
Even the ass-bags
who tried to kill you are not sick!
All right. set cover. But let him come.
BURK:
All right. step forward! Slowly!
Hey. hey. hey. keep it slow.
Moving slow. Everybody just take it easy.
That's far enough.
Okay. commodore.
You wanna get the lowdown or not?
Let's start with the ass-bags.
- They're al Qaeda. What's left of them.
- How many?
Fourteen altogether. but they're spread out
now to make you a welcoming party.
- Nobody's sick?
- We were all in Section 7...
...an isolated part of the camp
for high-level detainees.
We had our own food stocks. own facilities.
None of us came in contact with the virus.
Everybody else was evacuated.
We had the run of the place.
We?
Me and six other guards.
Subcontractors. private security.
At that point. we figured...
...no governments. no politics.
- We let them go.
- And they turned on you.
TEX:
That's what's left of my best friend.
Other guy's MIA.
- I'm the last man standing.
- So where the hell are they?
TEX:
Most went to guard the food warehouse...
...but three peeled off towards your ship
with rocket launchers.
- You're telling me this now?
- You're the one asking the questions.
Nathan James. Vulture One. be advised.
hostiles are armed with RPGs...
...en route to your whiskey.
Tiger One. Nathan James. cease pumping.
- Shut it down now.
- Secure fueling.
So. what can you tell me
about this food warehouse?
How to get in. but it's gonna mean
getting your hands dirty.
I've dirtied them before.
Tom Chandler.
CO. Nathan James. U.S. Navy.
Tex Nolan. Welcome to Gitmo.
Man. only got 15 PSI.
Shit. I'm at 9 percent.
All right. guys. listen to me.
We got a job to do here...
...and we're not finished yet.
No supplies. no vaccine.
No vaccine. no going home.
no seeing your families.
- Lieutenant Green. don't take any chances.
DANNY: Follow my lead.
We'll be out of here in less than 10. got it?
Let's do this thing.
Did he hear me?
He heard you.
LYNN:
Bridge. CCS. We're still taking on fuel.
Tiger Team. what the hell's going on there?
GARNETT: The valve is frozen.
We're working on it. sir!
Come on. Ma'am. stand back.
XO. recommend disengaging
the fuel hose on our end.
Spill oil into the harbor
while they have RPGs? Hell. no.
TAO. Bridge. We have hostiles incoming.
Find me a target.
Again. One. two...
Nathan James. the valve stem is shot. sir.
We cannot stop the fuel.
Incoming!
[GARNETT ROANING]
CHUNG:
Ma'am!
[GUNFIRE]
Nathan James. this is MPA.
Chief engineer's been hit.
We need the doc up here. ASAP!
TAO. give me a targeting solution
on that terminal.
- Aye. sir.
- OS-1. range and bearing to the terminal?
Rough bearing two-two-zero.
approximately 1500 yards.
They're going for the fuel tank.
They're gonna blow the ship!
CIC. Bridge. Where's my target acquisition?
- Slew left 30.
- Roger. left 30 degrees.
Bridge. surface target acquired.
Fire.
Tiger Team. Nathan James.
Doc Rios is en route. ETA five minutes.
Vulture. Cobra. Nathan James.
All known hostiles neutralized
in the vicinity of the fuel pier.
CHANDLER:
Vulture Team. copy that.
So where are they gonna be?
Oatmeal and baked beans.
It's the new women and children.
They're holed up in that warehouse.
They're gonna make us come and get them.
Captain.
Animals.
Revenge is best served cold.
Let's eat.
Lieutenant Green. you have everything I need.
Please get out of there now.
Cobra One. copy. Proceeding to extract.
[BARKS]
[GUNFIRE]
DANNY:
Go. go! Come on!
Go!
Sir. Cobra Team's trapped inside the hospital.
running out of air.
We located the shooters outside the hospital?
Have a target?
BARKER: Negative. sir.
- Patch me in to Green.
- I'm out of air!
- Two percent.
- Almost nothing.
- Couple of minutes. max!
I'm gonna peel off Vulture
to give you reinforcements.
Negative. They're too far away. They will
never get here in time. But I got an idea.
Copy that. Vulture Team preparing
to hit the warehouse. Lead the way.
Where are they?
[GUNFIRE]
Grenade!
DANNY: Cruz. what's your status?
CRUZ: On the stairs approaching the roof.
- Ten seconds out.
DANNY: Check.
We got this. boy.
No worries.
Troops are on the ropes.
Extracting now.
[ALARM BEEPING]
CRUZ:
We're in position. Stand by to engage.
[GUNFIRE]
[GROANS]
[GASPING]
[GUNSHOT]
DANNY:
He's hit! Man down! Man down!
Damn it! We need the doc out here!
Sir. he's with Tiger One
by the fueling station.
Commander...
...I worked a year in a trauma ward
in Mogadishu.
Gear up.
[GUNFIRE]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[GROANS]
Stay with me. Cruz. Just stay with me.
Get him stabilized. then get off the beach.
First whiff of hostilities. you are out. Got it?
I read you loud and clear. commander.
TAO. I want five-inch CIWS in surface mode
focused on that beach.
Aye. sir.
RACHEL: What have we got?
- What? Where's the doc?
At the fueling tank.
Your chief engineer was injured as well.
- Lay him down.
- Get him down.
DANNY: Here you go.
- You. hold that.
DANNY: Set up a perimeter.
- All right.
SMITH:
Yes. sir.
COSSETTI: Get over watch.
DANNY: Come on.
SMITH: Got the high point.
DANNY: He's gonna bleed out. Wait!
- Get the doc!
RACHEL: We don't have time to wait.
There's nothing a medic can do
that we cannot. If you want to help...
...hold him still and listen
to every word that I say.
Come on. Stay with me. Look at me.
You're gonna be all right.
[GRUNTS]
DANNY: Let's go. come on.
Blood pressure's dropping.
Hold that!
Going back in. Okay.
Hey. Come on. stay with me.
Look at me. Stay with me.
If you do not close this artery. he's dead.
Got it.
He's stabilized.
Hey. commodore.
Don't give them a damn thing.
This here is Amir. He's a big fan of IEDs
and mutilating American soldiers.
Amir. my name is Tom Chandler. U.S. Navy.
You don't want to do this.
Tex is the man who let you go
from your cells.
- He is no different from the others.
- Hey. feeling's mutual. you dirty--
Vulture Team. Nathan James.
I need a status update.
Vulture Team. Nathan James. Status?
CHANDLER: Nathan James. Vulture One.
We're at the food warehouse.
Just trying to deal with a little hostage
situation over here.
AMIR [OVER RADIO]: Who are you talking to?
CHANDLER: I'm answering my ship's call.
Otherwise. they'll panic.
start shelling the whole place.
- He wants a diversion.
CHANDLER: All we 're doing is talking.
- Let's not get anybody else killed here.
AMIR: No more talking to them. Talk to me!
Prepare the five-inch. Focus fire on
Building 35. Stand by for exact coordinates.
Nishioka. eyes on.
- Leave all food on this side of the building.
- Not enough of you to eat that in 10 lifetimes.
CHANDLER:
Look.
Amir. it's a new world now.
There's no good guys and bad guys.
Doesn't matter which side we were on.
We're all just trying to survive.
We don't want to hurt you any more
than you want to hurt us.
But you know I'm not leaving here
without my man.
- So when you let Tex go--
- If I let him go!
When you let him go. we'll be on our way.
I'll decide how much food we leave you with.
AMIR: No! Enough of this!
Listen to me. Amir.
You want the entire southwest
corner of the warehouse.
Focus fire Building 35. southwest corner.
That's almost half the food in the entire place.
Is that gonna make you happy?
No. You will leave all the food
on this side of the building. or he dies.
Well. now. see.
we got a bit of a problem with that.
Because there's one thing from the old world
that still applies today...
...something that will never change.
- Target acquired.
- Fire!
We don't negotiate with terrorists.
Clear!
Nice.
Yes.
Good work. good work.
I don't know how you feel about the water...
...but we sure could use your services.
Where you headed?
We got some things to do.
but when we're done. we're going home.
Yeah. I'll sign up for that.
CHANDLER: Nathan James. Vulture One.
Hostage situation resolved.
Thank you for the close shave.
We are inbound.
ALISHA [OVER PA]: Now go to your stations.
all special sea and anchor detail.
Nathan James will get under way at 1700.
All departments make manned and ready
special reports to the XO on the bridge.
Captain's on the bridge.
Hey.
We're loading up RHIBs and SDV subs.
Trucks are bringing over the food.
- Suppo thinks it's gonna last five. six weeks.
- And fuel?
We lost suction on the tank at 96 percent.
And the chief engineer took some shrapnel.
She's gonna be okay. though.
- Tough as nails. that one.
- When push comes to shove. they all are.
Gentlemen. apparently one of the machines
in the lab got tipped over.
Dr. Tophet is insists he needs time to secure
and recalibrate before we move the ship.
- How long?
- He says three to four hours.
Where's Dr. Scott?
Still in medical.
Was a tough call.
We did good today.
Captain. I'm picking up a contact headed
for the harbor. Negative electronic signature.
They're not operating their radar.
Cannot make a positive ID.
Vessel 21 miles southeast.
Guantanamo Bay...
...this is U.S. Navy warship one-five-one
hailing you on channel one-six.
Identify yourself. over.
WOMAN [OVER RADIO]:
This is British Naval vessel HMS Suffolk...
SLATTERY:
Confirm that.
...hull number five-two-five. IMO call sign
whiskey-echo-bravo-two-three-six.
None of us have been infected.
but we're running low on food.
We've been searching
for a place to replenish...
- ...and repair our radar.
- Confirmed. sir.
This is Commander Tom Chandler.
Commanding Officer. USS Nathan James.
We welcome you to Guantanamo Bay.
Wish you would've been here
a few hours ago. We could've used the help.
I assure you that next time.
we will be there for you...
...should you choose
to accept an association.
Well. we'll put some pot pies in the oven and
some fish and chips in the fryer. Come on in.
We can't go anywhere till the lab's fixed.
Let's prepare to greet our new friends.
XO has the lead.
Ow.
Oh. that stings.
RACHEL:
It's supposed to sting. I'm cleaning it.
- I don't need it cleaned.
- Yes. you do.
RIOS:
This is gonna sting a little.
CHANDLER: How you doing. eng?
- All right. sir.
- Doc says I'll be on my feet soon enough.
- No rush. We got it all under control.
She saved him.
She's gonna save us all. Right. Dr. Scott?
Well. hopefully. we'll save each other.
Real soulful. this one.
Never mind them good looks.
that brassy exterior.
Word?
I know. Don't do it again.
You don't have anything to prove...
...if that's what it was about.
And don't do it again.
TEX:
Hey! Nursey!
I need a cold compress here.
Spoils of war.
You know. I should be getting this stuff
ready for his family.
But. uh...
...there's nobody even to give it to.
MAN 1:
Captain's on the bridge.
- They in sight?
- Yeah.
I hear they serve Guinness on board.
Sir. E-DUB can't confirm the signature on
that vessel. but they don't think it's British.
CHANDLER:
It's the Russians.
Set General Quarters now!
General Quarters! General Quarters!
All hands. man your battle stations!
BARKER [OVER RADIO]:
Bridge. TAO.
SCUNK Alpha just energized
fire control radar.
- We're in their crosshairs.
MAN 2 [ON RADIO]: Captain Tom Chandler?
This is Commander Chandler.
Identify yourself immediately.
I'm sorry to have made
such a rude introduction...
...but I believe you have something
that I want.
Ripped By mstoll